Miklos Rozsa Papers
Miklos Rozsa Papers
- Correspondence-subject files, general correspondence
  - Clemens, Cyril, historian (Box 14)
  - [The] Clift Hotel (San Francisco, CA) (Box 14)
  - Cloud Nine Records (London, England) (Box 14)
  - Coates, Albert & Vera, musician (Box 14)
  - Cockcroft, Jennifer (Box 14)
  - Cockshott, Gerald, composer (Box 15)
  - Cocumarolo, Enzo, fan (Box 15)
  - Cohen, Arnaldo, musician (Box 15)
  - Cohen, Larry, producer (Box 15)
  - [The] College of Wooster (Wooster, OH) (Box 15)
  - Colon, Charles-David, writer (Box 15)
  - Columbia Artists Management Inc. (New York, NY) (Box 15)
  - Columbia Pictures (Box 15)
  - Columbia Records (Box 15)
  - Compinsky, Manuel, musician (Box 15)
  - Composers and Lyricists Guild of America, Inc (Hollywood, CA) (Box 15)
  - Confederation Internationale des Societes d'Auteurs et Compositueurs (Paris, France) (Box 15)
  - Consolidated Leather Mfg. Co. Inc. (New York, NY) (Box 15)
  - Consortium Recordings (Los Angeles, CA) (Box 15)
  - Constance Hope Associates (New York, NY), agent (Box 15)
  - Continental Casualty Co. (Chicago, IL) (Box 15)
  - Continental Insurance Co. (New York, NY) (Box 15)
  - Copland, Aaron, composer (Box 15)
  - Corlese, Luigi, composer (Box 15)
  - Corwin, Norman, writer (Box 15)
  - Craddock & Barnard (London, England) (Box 15)
  - [The] Crescendo Club (Los Angeles, CA) (Box 15)
  - Cribbens, Norman, journalist (Box 15)
  - Crosby, Ronald (Box 15)
  - Crown, John, musician (Box 15)
  - Crusade for Freedom, Inc. (New York, NY) (Box 15)
  - Csicery-Rónay, István, writer (Box 15)
  - Curtis Gallery and Library (Pasedena, CA) (Box 15)
  - Cusato, Mike, fan (Box 15)
  - Cziffra, Georges, Soleilka, and György, Jr., musician (Box 15)
  - Czinkota, Mihály, poet (Box 15)
  - D (Box 15)
  - D'Albert, François, musician (Box 15)
  - Dallas Symphony Orchestra (Box 15)
  - Damiani, Leo, musician (Box 15)
  - Dane, Jeffrey, writer (Box 15)
  - Davis, Carl, conductor (Box 15)
  - Davisson, Walther, musician (Box 15)
  - Day & Meyer-Murray & Young Corp (New York, NY) (Box 15)
  - de Crescenzo, Gianni, writer (Box 15)
  - De Kezdi, Elemér (Box 15)
  - de Peyer, Gervase, musician (Box 15)
  - de Toth, André, director (Box 15)
  - [The] De Vere Hotel (London, England) (Box 15)
  - Deak, Alexander (Box 15)
  - Deak & Co. of Los Angeles (Box 15)
  - De'ak Stephen and Margaret, musician (Box 15)
  - Deaky, Zsolt, musician (Box 15)
  - Decca Records, Inc. (Los Angeles, CA) (Box 16)
  - Delkas Music Publishing Company (Los Angeles, CA) (Box 16)
  - Deluxe Carpet, Upholstery Cleaning (Los Angeles, CA) (Box 16)
  - DeMary, Thomas (Box 16)
  - Demme, Jonathan, director (Box 16)
  - Déry, Paolo, musician (Box 16)
  - Detroit Symphony Orchestra (Detroit, MI), orchestra (Box 16)
  - Deutsch, Adolph, composer (Box 16)
  - DeWald, Frank, musician (Box 16)
  - Diners Club (New York, NY) (Box 16)
  - Di Sospiro, Madeda Mina, Marchesa, neighbor in Santa Margherita, Italy (Box 16)
  - Ditta Paganini (Genova, Italy) (Box 16)
  - Dittmar, M. A., fan (Box 16)
  - Dobay, Susan, artist (Box 16)
  - Dods, Marcus, musician (Box 16)
  - Doeckel, Ken, writer; see also Fitzpatrick, John (Box 16)
  - Doherty, Joe, fan (Box 16)
  - Dolan, Robert, composer (Box 16)
  - Dominguez, Albert, musician (Box 16)
  - Donath, Jeno, musician (Box 16)
  - Dorati, Antal, musician (Box 16)
  - Dorian, Frederick (Fritz), musician (Box 16)
  - Doris Harris Autographs (Los Angeles, CA) (Box 16)
  - Dorotheum (Vienna, Austria) (Box 16)
  - Double Life Music Corporation (Los Angeles, CA) (Box 16)
  - Drake, Ted (Box 16)
  - Drinkall, Roger, musician (Box 17)
  - Drissen, Margit, agent (Box 17)
  - Ducloux, Walter, musician (Box 17)
  - Duning, George, composer (Box 17)
  - Durand & Cie. (Paris, France) (Box 17)
  - Duvivier, Julien, director (Box 17)
  - E (Box 17)
  - E. J. Rothschild Agency (Hollywood, CA) (Box 17)
  - EMI Records Ltd. (London, England) (Box 17)
  - Editions Novos S.A. (Lausanne, Switzerland) (Box 17)
  - Editrice Musical Nord-Sud (Rome, Italy) (Box 17)
  - Edizioni Curci (Rome/Milan, Italy) (Box 17)
  - Einem, Gottfried von, composer (Box 17)
  - Elbogen, Paul, writer (Box 17)
  - Electro-Vox Recording Studios (Hollywood, CA) (Box 17)
  - Elizalde, John S., businessman (Box 17)
  - Elkan-Vogel Co. (Philadelphia, PA) (Box 17)
  - Elley, Derek, writer (Box 17)
  - Elmer Bernstein's Filmusic Collection (Calabasas, CA) (Box 17)
  - Elvers, Rudolf, writer (Box 17)
  - Ember Records, Ltd (London, England) (Box 17)
  - Enterprise Printers and Stationers, Inc. (Hollywood, CA) (Box 17)
  - Entr'acte Recording Society Inc. (Chicago, IL) (Box 17)
  - Erben, Friedrich-Carl, musician (Box 17)
  - Erdelyi, Barnábás (Box 17)
  - Ernest E. Gottlieb Musical Literature (Beverly Hills, CA) (Box 17)
  - Ernst Eulenburg Ltd. (London, England) (Box 17)
  - Estridge (London, England) (Box 17)
  - Eulenburg, Kurt, publisher (Box 17)
  - Evanghelatos, Antiochos, composer (Box 17)
  - Evans, Mark, writer (Box 17)
  - Everaert, Andre, fan (Box 17)
  - F (Box 18)
  - Faber Music Ltd. (London) (Box 18)
  - Famous Music Corporation (New York, NY) (Box 18)
  - Fankhauser, S. (Box 18)
  - Farnadi, Edith, musician (Box 18)
  - Farrant, Bernard (Box 18)
  - Farrow, Mia (Previn), actor (Box 18)
  - Federal Trade Commission (Box 18)
  - Fédération Internationale des Associations d'Auteurs de Films (Paris, France) (Box 18)
  - Feld, Otto, musician (Box 18)
  - Fenton, Larry (Box 18)
  - Fenyö, György (Box 18)
  - Ferber & Malota (Vienna, Austria) (Box 18)
  - Ferencsik, János, conductor (Box 18)
  - Ferrarese, Aldo, musician (Box 18)
  - Festival Internacional de Santander (Santander, Spain) (Box 18)
  - Fichter, Gerald (Box 18)
  - Field, Douglas (Box 18)
  - Film Music Notes (Box 18)
  - Filmharmonic 72 (London, England) (Box 18)
  - Finlason, Alex, family (Box 18)
  - Finston, Nat W., musician (Box 18)
  - Fischgrund, Sidney, lawyer (Box 18)
  - Fitzgerald, Brian and Mary (Box 18)
  - Fitzpatrick, John, writer; see also Doeckel, Ken; Miklós Rózsa Society (Box 18)
  - Földes, Andor, musician (Box 18)
  - Foldes, Lily (Box 18)
  - Földvári, Agnes (Agi) (Box 18)
  - Ford, John (Box 18)
  - Fortner, Wolfgang, composer (Box 18)
  - Fortnum & Mason Ltd. (London, England) (Box 18)
  - Foto-Geller (Düsseldorf, Germany) (Box 18)
  - Fournier, Mme Gaston (Box 18)
  - Fox, Donald B., businessman (Box 18)
  - Francescatti, Zino, musician (Box 18)
  - Frank P. Dow Companies (Los Angeles, CA) (Box 18)
  - Fränkisches Landesorchester (Nurnberg, West Germany) (Box 18)
  - Fred May Productions (Hollywood, CA), accountant (Box 18)
  - Freedman, William, businessman (Box 18)
  - Fricsay, Ferenc, musician (Box 18)
  - Fried, Alexander (Sandor) (Box 18)
  - Friedhofer, Hugo, composer (Box 18)
  - Friedman, Arnold P M.D., physician (Box 18)
  - G (Box 19)
  - G. Schirmer, Inc. (New York, NY) (Box 19)
  - GEMA (Berlin, W. Germany) (Box 19)
  - Gabbert, Klaus (Box 19)
  - Gabory, Magda, singer (Box 19)
  - Galea, Charles (Box 19)
  - Galerie Gerda Bassenge (Berlin, W. Germany) (Box 19)
  - Galeries Lafayette (Paris, France) (Box 19)
  - Gallagher, Jack, composer (Box 19)
  - Gallina, Pietro, artist (Box 19)
  - Garabedian, Gérard, fan (Box 19)
  - Garaguly, Carl, musician (Box 19)
  - Garcia, Russell, composer (Box 19)
  - Gardner, Florence, businessman (Box 19)
  - Geiger, Benno, writer (Box 19)
  - Geiringer, Karl, writer (Box 19)
  - Gelman, Harold, See also Metro-Goldwyn-Mayer Pictures (Culver City, CA) (Box 19)
  - General Phonograph (Los Angeles, CA) (Box 19)
  - Genn, Leo, actor (Box 19)
  - Gerhardt, Charles, musician (Box 19)
  - German, Ervin, musician (Box 19)
  - Gero, Steven "Pista" (Box 19)
  - Gerömé, Zsuzsa (Box 19)
  - Gertler, André, musician (Box 19)
  - Gibson, Appleby & Co. (London, England) (Box 19)
  - Gilardino, Angelo, musician (Box 19)
  - Gimpel, Jakob, musician (Box 19)
  - Gingold, Norbert, musician (Box 19)
  - Giovanni Pedevilla (Genova, Italy), See also Carlo Pedevilla, Spedizioni Marittime (Genova, Italy) (Box 19)
  - Glendale Federal Savings and Loan Association, Valley Branch (Studio City, CA) (Box 20)
  - Glendale Symphony Orchestra Association (Glendale, CA) (Box 20)
  - Globus Trading Corporation (New York, NY) (Box 20)
  - Godward, Tina May Walton and William, fan (Box 20)
  - Gold, Ernest, composer (Box 20)
  - Goldberg, Albert, critic; see also Los Angeles Times (Box 20)
  - Goldenberg, Harry (Box 20)
  - Goldsmith, Jerrald, composer (Box 20)
  - Gonder, Franz (Box 20)
  - González, Angelina (Box 20)
  - Goodwin, Ron, musician (Box 20)
  - Goossens, Eugene, musician (Box 20)
  - Goumard, Christian (Box 20)
  - Grabner, Hermann, composer (Box 20)
  - Gramegna, Lottario, M.D., physician (Box 20)
  - Granat, Endre, musician (Box 20)
  - Graunke, Kurt, composer (Box 20)
  - Gray, Gordon, publisher; see also Polydor Ltd (London, England); Willow Music (Pinner, Middlesex, England) (Box 20)
  - Gray, William, fan (Box 20)
  - Green, Johnny, composer (Box 20)
  - Green, Ray, See also Chambers Green Ltd.; publisher (Box 20)
  - Grevesmühl, Detlev, musician (Box 20)
  - Grossman-Vendry, Susanna (Box 20)
  - Group 5 Ltd. (London, England) (Box 20)
  - Gruenberg, Erich, musician (Box 20)
  - Guenzel, Dan, writer (Box 20)
  - Guild Publications of California, Inc. (Hollywood, CA) (Box 20)
  - Guy, Janet, copyist (Box 20)
  - Gyarmathy, Michel, director (Box 20)
  - H (Box 20)
  - Haake, Karl-Ernst (Box 20)
  - Hadjidakis, Manos, composer (Box 20)
  - Haenssler, Hans, writer (Box 20)
  - Hal Wallis Productions (Los Angeles, CA) (Box 20)
  - Halász, Kálmán, musician (Box 20)
  - Halperin, Martin, businessman (Box 20)
  - Hamer, Alan (Box 20)
  - Hamilton Philharmonic Orchestra (Hamilton, Ontario, Canada) (Box 21)
  - Hanneman, Karen, fan (Box 21)
  - Hannemann, Volker & Wolfram (Box 21)
  - Hanusa, Klaus and Birgit Kahle, director (Box 21)
  - Haranghy, Laszlo (Box 21)
  - Harding, Clifford (Box 21)
  - Hardy, Katharine, musician (Box 21)
  - Hargreaves, Jim (Box 21)
  - Harry H. Kem & Co., Ltd. (Beverly Hills, CA) (Box 21)
  - Harryhausen, Ray, producer (Box 21)
  - Hart, Henry, editor (Box 21)
  - Harth, Sidney, musician (Box 21)
  - Hatchards (London, England) (Box 21)
  - Hawkins, Arnold, writer (Box 21)
  - Hawkins, Robert, musician (Box 21)
  - Hayden, Bryan, fan (Box 21)
  - Hayes, Jack, composer (Box 21)
  - Hearst, Sigfried, agent (Box 21)
  - Heifetz, Jascha, musician (Box 21)
  - Heindorf, Michael, composer (Box 21)
  - Heindorf, Ray, musician (Box 21)
  - Helliniger, Mark, producer (Box 21)
  - Helmut Tenner (Heidelberg, W. Germany) (Box 21)
  - Heltai, Lilla (Box 21)
  - Hendl, Walter, musician (Box 21)
  - Herrmann, Bernard, composer (Box 21)
  - Herrmann, István (Box 21)
  - Herzlich, Gabriel, writer (Box 21)
  - Hessenberg, Kurt, writer (Box 21)
  - Hessischer Rundfunk (Frankfurt, W. Germany) (Box 21)
  - Hibberd, Maurice, photographer (Box 21)
  - Highland Park Symphony Assn. (Los Angeles, CA) (Box 21)
  - Hinkelman, Alan (Box 21)
  - Hittelman, Joseph, M.D., physician (Box 21)
  - Hodges, Simone (Box 21)
  - Hoenisch, Ernst, musician (Box 21)
  - Hoffman, Gary, musician (Box 21)
  - Hollywood Bowl (Hollywood, CA), see also Irish, Florence (Box 21)
  - [The] Hollywood Reporter (Hollywood, CA), newspaper (Box 21)
  - [The] Honolulu Symphony Society (Honolulu, HI) (Box 21)
  - Hornyik, Tibor (Box 21)
  - [The] Hospital of the Good Samaritan (Los Angeles, CA) (Box 21)
  - Hotel Regina Elena (Santa Margherita Ligure, Italy) (Box 21)
  - Hotel zum Storchen Zürich (Zürich, Switzerland) (Box 21)
  - Houseman, John, actor (Box 21)
  - Howard's Apartment Furnishings Inc. (Los Angeles, CA) (Box 21)
  - Howe, Lynne (Box 21)
  - Huba, Irma (Box 21)
  - Hudgins, Morgan, publicist (Box 21)
  - "Hugh" (Box 21)
  - Hungarian Embassy, London (Box 21)
  - Hungarian Consulate (Los Angeles, CA) (Box 21)
  - I (Box 22)
  - IKKA (Budapest, Hungary) (Box 22)
  - Iconographical Lexicon of Classical Mythology (Princeton, NJ), publisher (Box 22)
  - Immigration and Naturalization Service (Box 22)
  - Inball, Helga & Eliahu, musician (Box 22)
  - Incze, Sandor, writer (Box 22)
  - Indiana University (Bloomington, IN) (Box 22)
  - Indianapolis Symphony Orchestra (Indianapolis, IN) (Box 22)
  - Inland Revenue (England) (Box 22)
  - (H. M.) Inspector of Taxes (England) (Box 22)
  - Institut La Villan (Chesières-sur-Ollon, Switzerland) (Box 22)
  - Insurance Securities Incorporated (Oakland, CA) (Box 22)
  - Integrity Entertainment Corp. (Torrance, CA) (Box 22)
  - Interkoncert Budapest (Budapest, Hungary) (Box 22)
  - Internal Reveune Service (USA) (Box 22)
  - International Society for Contemporary Music (New York, NY) (Box 22)
  - Investors Overseas Services (Geneva Switzerland) (Box 22)
  - Irish, Florence, see also Hollywood Bowl (Hollywood, CA) (Box 22)
  - Ishitsubo, Keiko, fan (Box 22)
  - Ives, Ralph and Viola, editor (Box 22)
  - J (Box 22)
  - J______, Dot and Laurie (Box 22)
  - J. Paul Getty Museum (Malibu, CA) (Box 22)
  - Jackson, J.C. (Box 22)
  - Jadassohn, Kurt, see also SESAC (New York, NY) (Box 22)
  - James Vigeveno Galleries (Los Ajngeles, CA) (Box 22)
  - Jankay, Stephen and Edith, family (sister and brother-in-law) (Box 22)
    See also Rozsa, Edith.
  - Jansen, Heinz, see also Südwest-Ton-Studio (Stuttgart, Germany) (Box 22)
  - Jellinek, George, radio host (Box 22)
  - "Jenö" (Box 22)
  - Jensen, Marvel, musician (Box 22)
  - Jepson, Leslie H. and Stephen S. Webster, writer (Box 22)
  - Jochum, Eugen, conductor (Box 22)
  - John Barker & Co. Ltd. (London, England) (Box 22)
  - John Bell & Croyden (London, England) (Box 22)
  - John Feher & Co. (Washington, D.C.) (Box 22)
  - John Simon Guggenheim Memorial Foundation (New York, NY) (Box 22)
  - Jonas, Dorothy, musician (Box 22)
  - Jones, William A., fan (Box 22)
  - Judy Green Music (Hollywood, CA), fan (Box 22)
  - Jugokoncert (Belgrade, Yugoslavia) (Box 22)
  - Juhász, Elöd, writer (Box 22)
  - Julius Pollock Travel Bureau (Los Angeles, CA) (Box 22)
  - K (Box 23)
  - KLON Radio (Long Beach, CA), musician (Box 23)
  - Kabos, Ilona (Ilonka) and Louis Kentner, musician (Box 23)
  - Kanin, Garson and Ruth Gordon, writer (Box 23)
  - Kaper, Bronislaw, composer (Box 23)
  - Karajan, Herbert von, musician (Box 23)
  - Karinthy, Ferenc, writer (Box 23)
  - Karl Hnat & Co. (Vienna, Austria) (Box 23)
  - Karo Building Company (Los Angeles, CA) (Box 23)
  - Karzag, Dennis, realtor (Box 23)
  - Kaufman, Louis & Annette, musician (Box 23)
  - Kavanaugh, Paul, artist (Box 23)
  - Keith, Evelyn (Box 23)
  - Kelly, John (Box 23)
  - Kemp, Jeffery (Box 23)
  - Kendall, T.M., fan (Box 23)
  - Kern, Jerome, composer (Box 23)
  - Kerner, Imre (Box 23)
  - Kerpely, Jenö, musician (Box 23)
  - Kertész, István, musician (Box 23)
  - Kew, Lewis & Margaret, musician (Box 23)
  - Khan, Zain, fan (Box 23)
  - Khazraee, Goodarz, fan (Box 23)
  - Kigyósi, Árpád (Box 23)
  - Kilenyi, Edward, musician (Box 23)
  - Kilpatrick, Jack, musician (Box 23)
  - Kirkby, Trevor & Stan, fan (Box 23)
  - Kiss, Laslo and Nora (Box 23)
  - Klay, Andor (Box 23)
  - Kloss, Erich, conductor (Box 23)
  - Kodály Center of America (Wellesley, MA) (Box 24)
  - Kodjian, Varoujan, musician (Box 24)
  - Kohs, Ellis, composer (Box 24)
  - Koldys, Mark E., fan (Box 24)
  - Komlós, Péter, musician (Box 24)
  - Korda, Alexander, producer (Box 24)
  - Korda, Henry and Mo, artist (Box 24)
  - Korda, Vincent (Box 24)
  - Korda, Zoltan and Joan, director (Box 24)
  - Kormos, Violet and Eugene (Box 24)
  - Korn, Peter and Barbara, musician (Box 24)
  - Korngold, Gloria & Georgi, producer (Box 24)
  - Korody, Paul (Box 24)
  - Koster, Michael, fan (Box 24)
  - Kovacs Kezdi, Elmer, artist (Box 24)
  - Krachmalnick, Jacob & Joan, musician (Box 24)
  - Krasnoborski, Willam, writer (Box 24)
  - Kruger, Tarah, fan (Box 24)
  - Kubelik, Raphael, musician (Box 24)
  - Kubic, Gail, composer (Box 24)
  - Kun, Magda, actor (Box 24)
  - Kvortek, John, see Ave, Mildred (Box 24)
  - L (Box 24)
  - [The] L.V. Larson Music Company (Concord, CA) (Box 24)
  - LaBounty, Louis, fan (Box 24)
  - Lacomb, Alain (Box 24)
  - Lang, Fritz, director (Box 24)
  - Lange, Hans, conductor (Box 24)
  - Langot, Raymond (Box 24)
  - Larson, Randall, writer (Box 24)
  - Lasher, John (Box 24)
  - Laszlo, George M.D., physician (Box 24)
  - László, György, actor (Box 24)
  - Lauro, T., businessman (Box 24)
  - Lax, Henry, physician (Box 24)
  - Leeds Music Corporation (New York, NY) (Box 24)
  - Lefebvre, Linda, fan (Box 24)
  - Lefkowitz, Berke, Parker & Freedman (Beverly Hills, CA) (Box 25)
  - Lehnig, Wolfgang (Box 25)
  - Leiber, G.A. (Box 25)
  - Leinsdorf, Erich, musician (Box 25)
  - Lendvai, Ernö, historian; see also Tusa, Erzsébet (Box 25)
  - Lengyel, Melchior, writer (Box 25)
  - LeMoyne-Mills, Dolores, fan (Box 25)
  - Lexington Productions, Inc. (Los Angeles, CA) (Box 25)
  - Library of Congress (Washington, D.C.) (Box 25)
  - Lido Musique (Paris, France) (Box 25)
  - Liebermann, Rolf, composer (Box 25)
  - Liebner, Janos, musician (Box 25)
  - Ligeti, Désiré, singer (Box 25)
  - Ligeti, György, composer (Box 25)
  - Linehan, Randy W., fan (Box 25)
  - Linke, Manfred (Box 25)
  - Lodi-Fè, Maurizio and Helli, producer (Box 25)
  - Loeb, Carlo, physician (Box 25)
  - Loew's Incorporated (Culver City, CA), see also Metro-Goldwyn-Mayer Pictures (Culver City, CA) (Box 25)
  - London Film Productions, Inc. (New York, NY) (Box 25)
  - Lorant, Sari (Box 25)
  - Los Angeles Athletic Club (Los Angeles, CA) (Box 25)
  - Los Angeles, City of (Box 25)
  - Los Angeles, City, Bureau of Assessments (Box 25)
  - Los Angeles, City Humane Department (Box 25)
  - Los Angeles County Music Commission (Box 25)
  - Los Angeles, County of (Box 25)
  - Los Angeles, County of, Assessor (Box 25)
  - Los Angeles, County of, Los Angeles County Museum (Box 25)
  - Los Angeles, County of, Residential Personal Property (Box 25)
  - Los Angeles, County of, Tax Collector (Box 25)
  - Los Angeles Philharmonic Association (Los Angeles, CA) (Box 25)
  - Los Angeles Times (Los Angeles, CA), newspaper; see also Goldberg, Albert (Box 25)
  - Lotee (?) (Box 25)
  - Louis (?) (Box 25)
  - Lovas, Stephen (Box 25)
  - Love, Charles, fan (Box 25)
  - Ludwig Doblinger (Vienna, Austria) (Box 25)
  - Luhrs Insurance Agency (Phoenix, AZ) (Box 25)
  - Luleas, Miklos (?) (Box 25)
  - Lumkin, A.W. (Tony), recordist (Box 25)
  - Luther, Armin and Susan (Box 25)
  - M (Box 26)
  - MD, The Medical Newsmagazine (New York, NY) (Box 26)
  - MGM Records (Culver City, CA) (Box 26)
  - MGM Records-Recording (New York, NY), see MGM Records (Culver City, CA) (Box 26)
  - Mabee, Grace, see Film Music Notes (Box 26)
  - Mac Peterson & Associates (North Hollywood, CA) (Box 26)
  - Magee, John, poet (Box 26)
  - Magyar Forum (Budapest, Hungary) (Box 26)
  - Magyar Központi Híradó Rt. (Hungarian Federal News-reel, Budapest, Hungary) (Box 26)
  - Magyar Rádió (Budapest, Hungary) (Box 26)
  - Magyar, Thomas, musician (Box 26)
  - Mancini, Henry, composer (Box 26)
  - Mandel, John A., composer (Box 26)
  - von Manikowsky, H. and ? (Box 26)
  - Mann, Felix, physician (Box 26)
  - Mannix, Edgar J., producer (Box 26)
  - Mantica, Margit, writer (Box 26)
  - Marchisio, Luciano (Box 26)
  - Marcoux, Isabel, fan (Box 26)
  - Marcus, Abraham, lawyer (Box 26)
  - Maricopa County Tax Collector (Phoenix, AZ) (Box 26)
  - Marinello, Antonio, M.D., physician (Box 26)
  - Markham, Steve, musician (Box 26)
  - Markowitz, Richard, composer (Box 26)
  - Marks, Franklyn, composer (Box 26)
  - Marshall Ellis Limited (Montreal, QC, Canada) (Box 26)
  - Marston, Charles and Sallie Love (Bickel) (Box 26)
  - Martin, Herbert (Box 26)
  - Marvin Lauber Co. (North Hollywood, CA) (Box 26)
  - Masters Mart (Hollywood, CA) (Box 26)
  - Matas, Carlos, fan (Box 26)
  - Maté, Janos, musician (Box 26)
  - Math. Lempertz (Köln, Germany) (Box 26)
  - Mathieson, Muir, conductor (Box 26)
  - [The] Max Steiner Music Society (Los Angeles, CA) (Box 26)
  - Maxon, Thomas, fan (Box 26)
  - [The] May Company (Los Angeles, CA) (Box 26)
  - May, Joe and Mia, director (Box 26)
  - Mayer-Zanetti, Eugen (Box 26)
  - Mayo Clinic (Rochester, MN) (Box 26)
  - Mayor, G., M.D., physician (Box 26)
  - McDaniels, John Lea, fan (Box 27)
  - McKellip, Louise A. (Box 27)
  - Meadow Brook Music Festical and Theater (Rochester, MI) (Box 27)
  - Mechanical-Copyright Protection Society Limited (London, England) (Box 27)
  - Mehta, Mehli, conductor (Box 27)
  - Mehta, Zubin, conductor (Box 27)
  - Melichar, Alois, composer (Box 27)
  - Melnyk, Lubomyr, fan (Box 27)
  - Memoir Records Ltd., see Gray, Gordon (Box 27)
  - Menick, Stephen J., fan (Box 27)
  - Menuhin, Yehudi, musician (Box 27)
  - Merrill Lynch, Pierce, Fenner & Beane (Los Angeles, CA) (Box 27)
  - Mertens, Yvonne, actor (Box 27)
  - Metro-Goldwyn-Mayer Pictures (Culver City, CA), See also Gelman, Harold; Loew's Incorporated (Culver City, CA) (Box 27)
  - Meyer, Nicholas, writer; see also Radio Free Europe (London, England) (Box 27)
  - Mezöfy, Ladislaus and Therese, writer (Box 27)
  - Miami University (Oxford, OH) (Box 27)
  - Michel Swiss (Paris, France) (Box 27)
  - Midas Books (Speldhurst, Tunbridge Wells, Kent, England), publisher (Box 27)
  - Midland Bank Limited (London, England) (Box 27)
  - Mikes, George, writer (Box 27)
  - Miklós, Ilona (Box 27)
  - Miklós Rózsa Society, see also Doeckel, Ken (Box 27)
  - Milder, Sidney, fan (Box 27)
  - Millar, Cynthia, musician (Box 27)
  - Miller, Gary, fan (Box 27)
  - Miller, Richard, fan (Box 27)
  - Miller, Robert Wiley, composer (Box 27)
  - Million, E.K. (Box 27)
  - Milton Holland Fine Arts, Inc. (Beverly Hills, CA), gallery (Box 27)
  - Minkkinen, Timo, fan (Box 28)
  - Mirisch Films Limited (Iver Heath, Buckinghamshire, England) (Box 28)
  - Mohr, Richard, producer; see also Radio Corporation of America (Camden, NJ and New York, NY) (Box 28)
  - Moldenhauer, Hans, historian (Box 28)
  - Molnar, Ferenc and Maria, musician (Box 28)
  - Monta, Rudi (Box 28)
  - Monteux, Pierre, conductor (Box 28)
  - Monzó, Angel, fan (Box 28)
  - Moor, Elizabetta and Elemér (Box 28)
  - Morrison, Lester M.D., physician (Box 28)
  - Motion Picture Health and Welfare Fund (Los Angeles, CA) (Box 28)
  - Mott, Marie (Box 28)
  - Mouchet, Guy (Box 28)
  - Munck, Ernest O., businessman (Box 28)
  - Muriel Francis Publicity (New York, NY), publicist (Box 28)
  - Music For Pleasure (Feltham, Middlesex, England) (Box 28)
  - Music Library Recordings (San Francisco, CA) (Box 28)
  - [The] Music Shop (Hollywood, CA) (Box 28)
  - Musical America (New York, NY) (Box 28)
  - Musical Arts Society of La Jolla (La Jolla, CA) (Box 28)
  - Musical Courier (New York, NY) (Box 28)
  - Musicians Union Local 47 (Hollywood, CA) (Box 28)
  - N (Box 28)
  - N.F. Geria II (Munich, Germany) (Box 28)
  - N.V. Philips' Photographische Industrie (Baarn, The Netherlands) (Box 28)
  - Nagelman, A.C. (Box 28)
  - Nagy, Karoly (Box 28)
  - Nagy, Lajos (Box 28)
  - National Association for American Composers and Conductors (New York, NY) (Box 28)
  - National Automobile Insurance Company (Los Angeles, CA) (Box 28)
  - National Broadcasting Company, Inc. (New York, NY) (Box 28)
  - National Federation of Music Clubs (Norfolk, VA) (Box 28)
  - National Film Music Council, see Film Music Notes (Box 28)
  - National Film Preserve Ltd. (Telluride, CO) (Box 28)
  - National Symphony (Washington, D.C.) (Box 28)
  - National Travel Club, Inc. (Columbus, OH) (Box 28)
  - Needleman, Robert (Box 28)
  - Neel, John Edgar Jr., composer (Box 28)
  - Neill, Eric, fan (Box 28)
  - Neiman, Oscar, businessman (Box 28)
  - Nelson, Jack (Box 28)
  - Nestor, Greg, musician (Box 28)
  - New England Mutual Life Insurance Company (Boston, MA) (Box 28)
  - New York College of Music (New York, NY) (Box 28)